Andrew Baxter

Full-Stack Software Developer

Phone: 317-446-1938

Email: asbaxter1@gmail.com

Site: https://asbaxter.github.io/portfolio-site/
GitHub: https://github.com/asbaxter

Profile:

Full stack web developer how also has over four years of management experience. At my current company I have progressed rapidly through multiple departments, proving time and time again my abilities to lead an effective team, adapt to change, and solve problems. I bring professionalism, integrity, and work ethic to everything I do and can make a positive impact on any team.

Professional Experience:

FedEx Ground / P&D Coordinator / May 2022 - Present

Responsible for coordinating the operations between FedEx Ground and their service providers. Write detailed service reports that have been able to identify and correct multiple failing processes within our station. Using my service recaps, we were able to develop a method to reduce our miscellaneous delivery failures by around 7%.

FedEx Ground / Sort Manager / Oct 2021 – May 2022

* Responsible for maintaining the day-to-day operations of one of the most successful FedEx facilities in the world. Lead hundreds of employees by creating a culture of safety, efficiency, and integrity. Responsible for the quality and timely delivery of tens of thousands of costumer packages daily.

FedEx Ground / Area Manager / Jan 2021 – Oct 2021

- Developed and trained operations mangers to run efficient and well-organized areas, while maintaining company values and quality metrics.
- Increased weekend sort efficiency by about 10% by reengineering destinations to a more consolidated area, reducing sort times and total labor hours

FedEx Ground / Operations Manager / Dec 2018 – Jan 2021

- Successfully lead multiple teams of package handlers through different areas of the operation while always maintaining safety, efficiency, and integrity
- Reduced our controllable rehandle percentage by 50% using root cause analysis and trend tracking to better position and train facers (Jam Breakers)

We Do Windows / Field Supervisor / May 2018 - Feb 2020

Lead a team of window washers who gave hundreds of costumers a professional, high quality window washing experience.

Education:

Butler Executive Education (May 2022 – Present)

Full Stack Development

Ball State University (2014 – 2018)

100 credit hours completed towards, major in criminal justice and a minor in digital forensics

Skills:

*	HTML	*	Node.js	*	MongoDB
*	CSS	*	Express.js	*	React
*	JavaScript	*	MySQL	*	MERN
*	Python	*	Git	*	Bootstrap